Khawar Jatoi

Full-Stack Javascript Developer

github.com/khawarjatoi

92 301 776 6650

www.khawarjatoi.com

in linkedin.com/in/khawarjatoi

hey@khawarjatoi.com

Pakistan

ABOUT

I've been passionate and committed developer for more than 3 years and have been getting better at programming for most of the time. I may not know all the principles and patterns but I usually know how to find the things I need.

I'm strong in object oriented analysis, design, front-end development with (HTML5, CSS3, Javascript and React) as well as back-end development (Node.js, PHP), Relational Databases (MySQL, MariaDB) and Data Query Language (GraphQL).

EXPERIENCE

01/2020 - Present

Full-Stack Javascript Developer Freelance

- Contract work for web development.
- Mostly working with Javascript ecosystem(React, Node.js)

03/2017 - 12/2019 **Software Engineer**

Surface Art Engineering, Inc.

Worked as a software engineer and got involved in main project of company.

We spent two years developing a highly complex ERP system and several other projects.

03/2016 - 03/2017 **Desktop Application Developer** Freelance

- Worked as a Desktop Application Developer using C# and developed some applications for small enterprises using MetroFrameworkUi.
- These applications features were to keep track of inventory, customers and client's information, generate invoices, bills and offer sales reports.

EXPERTISE

WEB DEVELOPMENT

HTML, CSS3, Javascript, styled-components, React, Redux,

Next.js, React Final Form, Node.js, PHP

DATABASES Relational Databases (MySQL, MariaDB, MS SQL Server)

> NoSQL Databases (MongoDB) Data Query Language (GraphQL)

VERSION CONTROLS Git, SVN

OTHER JWT, OAuth, Prisma Mail Server Setup, Ubuntu,

PROJECTS

Personal Site http://www.khawarjatoi.com #React #styled-components #Next.js #Heroku	Built personal portfolio to practice React and showcase what I've been working lately.
Ecommerce Website Sample https://bluestarhft.herokuapp.com Real-Life e-commerce website built with MERN Stack #React #Redux #React-Final-Form #Next.js #MongoDB #Node.js #Heroku	 An ecommerce website developed using MERN Stack Developed a dashboard with product management capabilities and user authentication. An easy-to-use checkout with discount tools Search and sort to easily find categories Manage categories and sub-categories Feature categories within navigation or on the homepage Search and sort to easily find products in certain categories or with specific attributes
ERP System A system of integrated applications to manage all facets of operation in a single database, application and user interface. #PHP #Javascript #MySQL #Roundcube #Postfix #Dovecot #Gerbv #PHPSpreadSheet	 Worked with PHP, jQuery and MySQL for storage. Worked on setting up a secure mail server powered by open source technologies like Roundcube, Postfix, and Dovecot. I learned a lot about communication protocols like IMAP or SMTP along the way. Integrated ERP system into Roundcube client. Developed REST APIs and integrated third-party APIs. Worked with open source technologies like gerbv(process Gerber files), PhpSpreadSheet(read and write to spreadsheets), fancyapps(present media) and many more.
EtherCalc Authentication and Dashboard integration EtherCalc is a Real-Time open source web spreadsheet. #LiveScript #Node.js #Express #MongoDB	 I developed few pieces of software on the company scale level. Developed APIs for authentication and data securtiy. Developed dashboard for sheets management. Fixed sheet disappearing and tabs renaming issues in EtherCalc

EDUCATION

2015 Masters In Science (MCS)

Institute of Southern Punjab Multan

Computer Science

2018 Self-Learning

Internet

Node.js, Express, React.js, Next.js